Ryan Hanson

Dallas, OR

Summary

Senior at Western Oregon University majoring in Computer Science and minoring in Information Systems. I have experience in both full stack web development and ethical hacking in academic environments. I'm a trustworthy and reliable hard worker that can be counted on as a member of a team.

Education

Western Oregon University, BS Computer Science

(SEP 2020 - JUN 2024 (Expected) | Monmouth, OR)

Major: Computer Science | Minor: Information Management

Institutional GPA: 3.68 | Major GPA: 3.78 | Upper Division GPA: 3.95

Coursework: Fundamentals of Web Design, Social History of Computing, Data Structures, Computer Organization, Computer Ethics,
Programming Languages, Information Management (CS Course), Software-Language & Tools, Microservices Architecture,
Information Assurance & Security, Algorithms, Operating Systems & Networking, Software Design & Testing, Networks, Applied
Discrete Mathematics, Software Engineering I, Information Management I (IS Course), Information Management II (IS Course),
Cybersecurity Fundamentals, Information Systems Automation, Systems Analysis, Ethical Hacking, Intro to Computer Security,
Network Security

Work Experience

Zumiez | Sales Associate

(NOV 2018 - AUG 2019 | Salem, OR)

- Provide assistance to customers
- Maintain a clean shopping environment
- Stock merchandise
- Handle cash and tills

Dutch Bros Coffee | Broista

(AUG 2019 - JAN 2022 | Salem, OR)

- Provide drinks and baked goods to customers
- Uphold corporate values by maintaining good work ethic and attitude
- Maintain efficiency and urgency without forfeiting quality of work or product
- Handle cash and tills
- Communicate with customers and coworkers

Skills & abilities

- Languages: C#, Python, JavaScript, MSSQL, MySQL, C/C++
- Development Tools: Git, VSCode, Docker
- Other Skills: CLI [Unix/Linux/Windows], Cyber Security, Communication, Time Management, Problem Solving

Projects

Shell Program (Operating Systems and Networking) $\mid C$

(MAY 2023)

- Developed a program in C that functions as a shell, being able to take up to 16 actual shell commands that are either piped (|), outputted (>), ran in the background (&), or delimited with a semicolon (;) to indicate the end of a set of commands. All commands inputted into shell program provide the same output as though the input was executed directly into an actual shell.
- Gained experience forking processes, specifically by controlling and managing the parent process and the many child processes for them to all work together to produce a smooth and seamless-feeling program.

Full Stack Web Application (Final for Software Engineering I) | C#, .NET, SQL, Swagger, Azure

(DEC 2023)

- Developed a 'Coffee Shop Ordering System' in which orders come in and are displayed in an easy to traverse UI, with another UI that
 allows employees from different stations to see which items they must fulfill for the current orders. The application enables employees
 to click off which items they've fulfilled, so that they can easily communicate with their crew.
- Utilized techniques to convert JSON data into C# classes that mapped to an SQL database. Developed using the Test-Driven Development approach.
- Gained experience with using living documentation and understanding user stories to drive the development of features, as well as
 gained experience using Azure to host the application.